#### Coordonnées

louis-m\_chateauvieux@hotmai

www.linkedin.com/in/lm-dechateauvieux (LinkedIn)

# Principales compétences

Launches

Product Communication

**Product Training** 

## Languages

Anglais (Full Professional)

Espagnol (Elementary)

Français (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

Narrative Design Certified

Product Focus Certified Product Manager

Certificat de dégustation du vin - approche intuitive et géo-sensorielle

- Sommelier Caviste BC01

Leadership in Product Marketing certified

**User Onboarding 101** 

# Louis-Marie de Chateauvieux

Product Marketer spécialisé en Go-To-Market strat de produits SaaS France

## Résumé

Lead PMM avec 8 ans d'expérience dans la tech et le SaaS, spécialisé dans les stratégies de lancement, le positionnement produit et l'adoption. Solide expertise en collaboration transverse, approche PLG et création de messages orientés client pour générer engagement, croissance et product-market fit.

# Expérience

## Mangopay

Lead Product Marketing Manager - Risk & Fraud Prevention Universe septembre 2023 - Present (2 ans)

Paris, Île-de-France, France

As a Lead Product Marketing Manager in the Risk Universe, my core responsibilities encompass:

- Leading the development of engaging narratives for our Risk, Fraud
   Prevention, Identity Verification, and Strong Customer Authentication solutions.
- Strategizing and executing go-to-market plans for risk management products in collaboration with cross-functional teams.
- Guiding market research efforts to understand customer fraud detection, identity verification, and authentication challenges.
- Crafting persuasive content and messaging to boost awareness and adoption of our risk solutions

Overseeing the creation of sales training materials that empower our team to effectively communicate the value of our fraud prevention and identity verification offerings.

- Ensuring customer-facing teams have the necessary information and content to support new features and promote customer success

- Participating in business processes by delivering product demos and fostering an efficient beta strategy

Manitoring market trends and customer foodback to optimize our rick.

Monitoring market trends and customer feedback to optimize our risk management product marketing strategies continually.

- Fostering strong relationships with customers, partners, and internal teams to drive success in the risk, fraud prevention, identity verification, and SCA space.

Product Marketing Alliance
Ambassadeur Product Marketing Alliance
mars 2021 - Present (4 ans 6 mois)
Londres, Angleterre, Royaume-Uni

**AB Tasty** 

3 ans

Senior Product Marketing Manager juillet 2022 - août 2023 (1 an 2 mois) Ville de Paris, Île-de-France, France

Among many different tasks, my main missions were concentrated around 4 parts of

the PMM role.

- Product expert and evangelist: Orchestrate product launches, aligning sales, marketing and product, translating technical details and features into stories that resonate with customers and differentiate our product in the marketplace.
- Sales and customer-facing staff enabler: write standardized product materials including messaging and positioning documents, sales sheets, content summaries, storyboards.
- Market expert and competition champion. I invest time to develop expertise on users and buyers - and I know how to crush the competition!
- Voice of the customer: I conducted interviews (win/loss/product review and roadmap presentation) to gather valuable feedback to feed my market expertise.

Besides that I had many other missions, like:

- Helping partners and client teams present the roadmap and upcoming investment areas.
- Participate in the redesign of the positioning and the creation of a striking narrative.

- Lead the Product Led Growth strategy and manage the free trial users. Build and evolve a sharp product tour and design the best possible first experience on one of our products.
- Onboard new employees on one of our products.

Product Marketing Manager septembre 2020 - juillet 2022 (1 an 11 mois) Paris

#### Splio

Product Marketing Manager juillet 2018 - septembre 2020 (2 ans 3 mois) Région de Paris, France

I was in charge of Product message strategies and communication. My main tasks were:

- Creating market-facing materials and content (sales presentations, product videos, sales proposal templates, datasheets, sales scripts, USPs, etc.)
- · Sales training and enablement
- product Positioning
- Market Analysis

I was also accountable for the creation and maintenance of:

- Sales onboarding materials and sales kits
- · Internal facing knowledge sharing
- · Customer segmentation and use cases
- Competitive intelligence (including battle cards)
- Capturing client case studies and testimonials with the product team.

#### Webedia

Product Marketing Manager mobile gaming juillet 2017 - juin 2018 (1 an) Région de Paris, France

- Responsable du contenu des applications
- Mise en place et gestion de la stratégie CRM
- Conception produit avec le Game Designer & des DA
- Élaboration de la roadmap et hiérarchisation des fonctionnalités à implémenter.
- Suivit des projets avec le chef de projet et les développeurs.
- · Ecoute des retours utilisateurs
- Suivi de l'audience quotidienne et des autres indicateurs business

Reporting hebdomadaires et Trimestriels

## Equancy

Consultant junior Marketing & Digital strategy janvier 2017 - juillet 2017 (7 mois)

Région de Paris, France

- Benchmark
- Recommandations et stratégie digitale
- Newsletters et revues de presses sur des sujets digitaux pour usage interne et externe
- Animation de workshops et réunions clients
- Veille stratégique

#### Groupe Numericable-SFR

Assistant chef de produit Cloud Gaming et contenus digitaux août 2015 - janvier 2016 (6 mois)

campus SFR saint Denis

- · Analyse indicateurs business et reporting
- · Gestion partenariats jeux mobiles
- · Benchmark, veille concurrentielle
- Suivi des Roadmaps
- · Gestion de contenu

#### Ubisoft

Assistant digital Marketing Manager janvier 2015 - juin 2015 (6 mois)

Région de Paris, France

- Digital Marketing,
- Web Marketing,
- Briefs de newsletters, d'adservers,
- Benchmark,
- Analyse des KPI site web et reseaux sociaux,
- Online advertising,
- Gestion de la cohésion au sein des services et vis-à-vis des filiales internationales.
- Rédaction des mails et des documents en Anglais.

Agence Care
Digital Marketing Consultant
mai 2014 - juillet 2014 (3 mois)

Paris Area, France

#### Expériences acquises:

Web Marketing et digital marketing, Benchmark, Audit digital, Référencement Web, Prospection clientèle, gestion média, Campagnes SEO, SEA, redaction de note d'intentention, achat media,

Université Numérique Paris Ile-de-France, Paris 1 Pantheon Sorbonne

Professeur d'informatique novembre 2013 - juin 2014 (8 mois)

Cours dispensés auprès d'élèves de première année en droit 9h par semaine en plus de correction de copies et de surveillance d'examens

#### Diplomeo

Gestionnaire relation client juillet 2012 - juillet 2013 (1 an 1 mois) Région de Paris, France

- · Gestion des Leads
- · SEO / SEM
- · Gestion du Back-office
- Suivi clientèle
- Management relation Client
- · Gestion des bases de données.

# Formation

Audencia Nantes Ecole de Management

Master marketing for producter manager, Marketing / gestion du marketing, général · (2014 - 2017)

Université Paris 1 Panthéon-Sorbonne

licence, gestion et économie des entreprises · (2012 - 2014)